In the last video,
再上一个视频中
you saw the equations for back propagation.
你已经看到了反向传播的公式
In this video, let's go over some intuition using
在这个视频中 我将增强你对于公式的理解和直觉
the computation graph for how those equations were derived.
我将用计算图来告诉你这些公式是如何得到的
This video is completely optional.
这个视频完全是可选的
So, feel free to watch or not.
所以看不看由你决定
You should be able to do the whole work either way.
而且你不看也能够完成反向传播的整个过程
So, recall that when we talk about logistic regression,
回忆一下我们讲逻辑回归的时候
we had this forward pass where we compute z,
我们通过前向传播计算z
then a and then the loss.
然后计算a 最后计算loss（损失）
And then to take the derivatives,
然后为了计算导数
we had this backward pass where we could first compute da,
我们使用了反向传播 我们先计算da
and then go on to compute dz,
然后计算dz
and then go on to compute dw and db.
接着计算dw和db
So, the definition for the loss was L of a,
这里的损失函数定义为L(a,y)
y equals negative y log a minus one,
等于 -yloga 减去
minus y times log one minus a.
(1-y) 乘以 log(1-a)
So, if you are familiar with
所以 如果你熟悉
calculus and you take the derivative of this with respect to a,
微积分的话 你会求这个函数关于a的偏导数
that would give you the formula for da.
那么你会得到 da 的式子
So, da is equal to that.
所以da等于这个式子
And if you actually figure out da in calculus you could show that this is
如果你把 da 求出来的话 你可以得出
negative y over a plus one minus y over one minus a.
它等于 -y/a + (1 - y) / (1 - a)
You just kind of derive that from calculus by taking derivatives of this.
所以你只需计算这个式子的导数 就能得到这个结果
It turns out when you take another step backwards to compute dz,
而当你更进一步计算 dz 时
we did work out that dz is equal to a minus y. I did explain why previously,
我们之前计算过 dz 等于 a-y 我之前也解释过原因
but it turns out that from the chain rule of calculus dz is equal
但是通过链式求导 dz等于
to da times g prime of z.
da 乘以 g'(z)
Where here g of z equals sigmoid of z
这里的g(z)等于sigmoid(z)
is our activation function for this output unit in logistic regression, right?
在逻辑回归中 它是这个输出单元的激活函数
So, just remember this is still logistic regression where we have x1, x2,
所以记住这里仍然是逻辑回归 我们有x1, x2
x3 and then just one sigmoid unit and that gives us a,
x3 然后这里只有一个sigmoid输出单元 从它得到a
will gives us Y hat
即得到 y^
So, here the activation function was a sigmoid function.
所以这里的激活函数是一个sigmoid函数
And as another side,
另一方面
only for those you familiar with the chain rule of calculus
你只需掌握微积分中的链式求导法则即可
the reason for this is because A is equal to sigmoid of Z.
这个式子成立的原因是 a等于sigmoid(z)
And so, partial of L with respect to z is equal to partial of
所以 L关于z的偏导数 等于
L with respect to a times da, DZ.
L关于a的偏导数乘以da/dz
This is a is equal to sigmoid of z,
这里的函数是 a=sigmoid(z)
this is equal to d/dz,
这里等于d/dz
g of z, which is equal to g prime of z.
乘以g(z) 也就是等于g'(z)
So, that's why this expression which is DZ in our code is equal
所以 这就是为什么在代码中 dz等于
to this expression which is da in our code times g prime of z.
这个式子 即代码中的da 然后乘以g'(z)
And so this is just that.
所以这个式子就等于上面的式子
So, that last derivation would made sense only if
所以 你应该能够理解刚刚的推导
you're familiar with calculus and specifically the chain rule from calculus.
但前提是你熟悉微积分 特别是要了解链式求导法则
But if not don't worry about it.
但是不会的话也不用担心
I'll try to explain the intuition wherever it's needed.
因为在有需要的时候 我一定会尽力向你解释
And then finally having computed dz for logistic regression,
所以最后 我们计算出了逻辑回归中的 dz
we will compute dw which turns out was
接下来我们要计算dw
dz times x and db which is just dz when you have a single training example.
由此可得 dw = dz * x 而 db = dz 这是只有一个样本时的结果
So, that was logistic regression.
所以 这就是逻辑回归
So, what we're going to do when computing back
我们要做的就是 当我们对
propagation for a neural network is a calculation a lot like
神经网络进行反向传播时 我们会做很多与此相似的计算
this but only we'll do it twice because now we have not x going to an output unit,
但是我们只需计算两次 因为这里的x不是输出单元
but x going to a hidden layer and then going to an output unit.
这里的x是隐含单元 然后才是输出单元
And so instead of this computation being sort of one step as we have here,
所以不同的是 我们在这里只计算了一次
we'll have you know two steps here in this kind of a neural network with two layers.
而对于这个两层的神经网络 我们需要计算两次
So, in this two layer neural network that is we have the input layer,
在这个两层的神经网络中 有输入层
a hidden layer and then output layer.
一个隐藏层 以及一个输出层
Remember the steps of a computation.
记住计算的步骤
First you compute z1 using this equation,
首先你用这个等式计算z1
and then compute a1 and then you compute z2.
然后计算a1 接着计算z2
And notice z2 also depends on the parameters w2 and b2.
注意 z2 也受参数 w2 和 b2 的影响
And then base on z2,
然后在z2的基础上
compute a2 and then finally that gives you the loss.
计算a2 最后你就能得到损失值loss
What backpropagation does is it will go backward to compute da2 and then dz2,
所以反向传播要做的就是 反向计算da2 然后dz2
and then you go back to compute dw2 and db2,
然后再接着反向计算 dw2 和 db2
go backward to compute da1,
再反向计算 da1
dz1 and so on.
dz1 等等
We don't need to take the derivatives as respect to
注意我们不需要计算关于
the input x since the input x for supervised learning are so fixed.
输入x的偏导数 因为对于监督学习 输入x是完全确定的
so we're not trying to optimize x so we won't bother to take the derivatives
所以我们不会去最优化x 也就无需求它的导数
At least, for supervised learning,
至少对于监督学习 我们
we respect X. I'm going to skip explicitly computing da2
不需要这样做 下面我要跳过计算da2的过程
If you want, you can actually compute
如果你想亲自算一次 你可以
da2 and then use that to compute dz2 but, in practice,
计算da2 然后用它计算dz2 但在实际中
you could collapse both of these steps into one step so you end up
你可以把这些步骤合到一个步骤中去 所以你会得到
at dz2= a2-y, same as before.
dz2等于a2-y 这和之前相同
And, you have also,
你也会得到
I'm going to write dw2 and db2 down here below.
我将把dw2以及db2写在这儿下面
You have that dw2=dz2*a1,
这里有dw2等于dz2乘以a1
transpose, and db2=dz2.
的转置 然后db2等于dz2
This step is quite similar for logistic regression where we had
这和之前的逻辑回归非常相似 我们有
that dw = dz * x except that now,
dw = dz * x 除了现在
a1 plays the role of x and there's an extra transpose there because the
a1充当了x的角色 然后这里还有一个额外的转置
relationship between the capital matrix W and our individual parameters w,
因为矩阵 W 和我们单个的参数 w 的关系
there's a transpose there, right?
这里应该还有个转置
Because w is equal to a row vector in the case of the logistic regression with a single output.
因为在只有一个输出的逻辑回归中 这里的w是一个行向量
dw2 is like that, whereas,
dw2像这样 然而
w here was a column vector so that's why it has an extra transpose for a1,
这里的w是一个列向量 这就是为什么这里的a1有个额外的转置
whereas, we didn't for x here for logistic regression.
然而在逻辑回归中 我们却没有对x进行转置
So this completes half of backpropagation.
现在我们完成了反向传播的一半
Then, again, you can compute da1 if you wish.
然后我们可以计算da1
Although, in practice, the computation for da1 and
然而在实际中 计算da1和
the dz1 are usually collapsed into one step and so
dz1 通常合并到一步中去计算
what you'll actually implement is that DZ1=W2,
所以实际上你需要做的是 dz1=W2
transpose times dz2, and then times an element
的转置 乘以dz2 然后
wide's product of G1 prime of Z1.
和g1'(z1)进行元素对应相乘
And, just to do a check on the dimensions, right?
记住检查一下各个量的维度
If you have a neural network that looks like this,
如果你有一个像这样的神经网络
I'll put Y hat if so.
将y^作为输出
If you have N0, NX=N0 input features,
如果你有nx=n0个输入特征
N1 hidden units,
n1个隐含单元
and N2 so far.
然后是n2
N2, in our case,
在这个例子中 n2
just one output unit,
只有一个输出单元
then the matrix W2 is (N2,N1) dimensional,
所以矩阵W2的维度为(N2,N1)
Z2 and therefore DZ2 are going to be (N2,N1) by one dimensional.
而z2以及dz2的维度均为(N2,N1)
This really is going to be a one by one
然后这里是(1,1)
when we are doing binary classification, and Z1 and therefore also
前提是我们在做二分类 然后z1
DZ1 are going to be N1 by one dimensional, right?
以及dz1的维度均为(N1,1)
Note that for any variable foo and D foo always have the same dimension.
所以对于任何的变量foo以及dfoo 它们的维度都是相同的
That's why W and DW always have the same dimension and similarly,
这就是为什么w和dw拥有相同的维度 同样的
for B and DB and Z and DZ and so on.
b和db 以及z和dz 也都是这样的
To make sure that the dimensions of this all match up,
为了确保矩阵的维度都符合计算要求
we have that DZ1=W2 transpose times DZ2
我们有dz1等于W[2]的转置乘以dz2
and then this is an element wide's product times G1 prime of Z1.
然后这里再和g1'(z1)进行对应元素相乘
Matching the dimensions from above,
为了满足上面的维度
this is going to be N1 by one is equal to W2 transpose,
这里为(N1,1)等于W2的转置
we transpose of this so there's going to be N1 by N2 dimensional.
我们将这个进行转置 所以这里的维度是(N1,N2)
DZ2 is going to be N2 by one dimensional and then this,
而dz2的维度将为(N1,1) 然后
this is the same dimension as Z1.
这和z1的维度是一样的
This is also N1 by one dimensional so element wide's product.
因为要进行对应元素相乘 所以这里的维度也是(N1,1)
The dimensions do make sense, right?
现在这些维度都正确了 对吧
N1 by one dimensional vector can be obtained by
一个维度为(n1,1)的向量可以由
N1 by N2 dimensional matrix times N2 by one because the product of
维度为(n1,n2)的矩阵和维度为(n2,1)的矩阵相乘得到 因为
these two things gives you an N1 by one dimensional matrix and so this becomes
这两者的乘积将得出一个维度为(n1,1)的矩阵 所以这就成了
the element wide's product of two N1 by one dimensional vectors,
两个维度为(n1,1)的向量对应元素的乘积
and so the dimensions do match.
所以这里的维度是符合要求得
One tip when implementing a back prop.
有个关于反向传播的小提示
If you just make sure that the dimensions of your matrices match up,
如果你想确定你的矩阵的维度在计算时是正确的
so you think through what are the dimensions of
你需要考虑各个矩阵
the various matrices including W1, W2, Z1,
的维度 包括W1 W2 z1
Z2, A1, A2 and so on and just make sure
z2 a1 a2 等等 一定要确保
that the dimensions of these matrix operations match up,
各个矩阵的维度是正确的
sometimes that will already eliminate quite a lot of bugs in back prop.
而有时候在反向传播中的bug已经很少了
All right. This gives us the DZ1 and then finally,
好了 我们由此得到dz1
just to wrap up DW1 and DB1,
最后将dw1和db1合起来
we should write them here I guess,
我们写在这里
but since I'm running of the space right on the right of the slide,
幻灯片上的空间已经快被我用完了
DW1 and DB1 are given by the following formulas.
dw1和db1由下面的公式给出
This is going to be equal to the DZ1 times X transpose
这个将等于dz1乘以x的转置
and this is going to be equal to DZ1.
而这个等于dz1
You might notice a similarity between these equations and these equations,
你可能已经注意到了 这些等式和这些等式是相似的
which is really no coincidence because X
这并不是巧合 因为在这里x
plays the role of A0 so X transpose is A0 transpose.
充当了a1的角色 所以x的转置就是a0的转置
Those equations are actually very similar.
这些等式其实是相似的
That gives a sense for how backpropagation is derived.
所以 以上就是反向传播的推导
We have six key equations here for DZ2, DW2,
这里有六个重要的公式 用于计算dz2 dw2
DB2, DZ1,DW1 and D1.
db2 dz1 dw1 以及 db1
Let me just take these six equations and copy them over to the next slide. Here they are.
现在我把这些公式复制一份 放到下一张幻灯片里面
So far, we've derived backpropagation,
目前 我们已经推导了反向传播
for if you are training on a single training example at a time,
但是这个推导只是关于一个样本的
but it should come as no surprise that rather than working on a single example at a time,
但是无需惊讶 我们通常不只处理一个样本
we would like to vectorize across different training examples.
我们将把不同的训练样本向量化
We remember that for forward propagation,
还得在前向传播的时候
when we're operating on one example at a time,
我们一次只处理一个样本
we had equations like this as was say A1=G1 of Z1.
我们有这样的公式 a1=g1(z1)
In order to vectorize,
为了能向量化
we took say the Zs and stacked them up in
我们把这些z堆在一起
columns like this onto Z1M and call this capital Z.
像这样放到列中 直到z[1][m] 记为大写的Z
Then we found that by stacking things up in columns
我们发现将这些放入列当中
and defining the capital uppercase version of this,
然后定义一个大写的矩阵版本
we then just had Z1=W1 X + B1
我们就得到Z[1] = W[1]X + B[1]
and A1=G1 of Z1, right?
然后A[1]=g1(Z1)
We define the notation very carefully in this course to make sure that
在这门课中 我们细心地定义了这些符号 为的是
stacking examples into different columns of a matrix makes all this work out.
能够把所有的样本都放入矩阵的列中 然后方便计算出来
It turns out that if you go through the math carefully,
值得一提的是 如果你认真地推导数学公式
the same trick also works for backpropagation so the vectorize equations are as follows.
这个技巧也同样适用于反向传播 所以向量化的公式如下所示
First, if you take these DZs for different training examples and stack
首先 如果你将这些不同样本的z放到
them as the different columns of a matrix and the same for this and the same for this,
矩阵的不同列当中 对这两个也做同样的处理
then this is the vectorize implementation and then here's the definition for,
然后这就是向量化后的版本 然后这里是
or here's how you can compute DW2.
用于计算dW[2]的式子
There is this extra 1/M because the cost function J is
这里有个1/m是因为 误差函数J定义为
this 1/M of sum for Y = one through M of the losses.
1/m 乘以 y从1到m的损失函数的和
When computing the derivatives,
当计算导数的时候
we have that extra 1/M term just as we did when we were
这里的1/m就和我们在计算
computing the weighted losses for the logistic regression.
逻辑回归中损失值的权重之和是相同的
That's the update you get for DB2.
这是计算db2的新公式
Again, some of the DZs and then with a 1/M and then DZ1 is computed as follows.
同样地 将dz放在一起 然后加上1/m 然后dz1按如下方式计算
Once again, this is an element wide's product only whereas previously,
再次注意 这里和之前一样是元素对应相乘
we saw on the previous slide that this was an N1 by one dimensional vector.
在上个幻灯片中 这个是一个 n1 x 1 维的向量
Now, this is a N1 by M dimensional matrix.
现在这是一个 n1 x m 维的矩阵
Both of these are also N1 by M dimensional.
这两个都是 n1 x m 维的矩阵
That's why that asterisk is element wide's product and then finally,
这就是为什么这个星号代表对应的元素相乘
the remaining two updates.
最后还有两个新公式
Perhaps it shouldn't look too surprising.
可能这看起来没什么好惊讶的
I hope that gives you some intuition for how the backpropagation algorithm is derived.
我希望这能够让你对反向传播能够有个更深入的了解
In all of machine learning,
在所有的机器学习算法中
I think the derivation of the backpropagation algorithm
我认为反向传播算法的推导
is actually one of the most complicated pieces of math I've seen,
是我见过的最复杂的推导
and it requires knowing both linear algebra as well as
推导反向传播需要掌握线性代数以及
the derivative and matrices to re-derive it from scratch from first principles.
导数和矩阵的知识 并需要从最初始的概念开始做起
If you are an expert in matrix calculus,
如果你精通矩阵微积分
using this process, you might prove the derivative algorithm yourself,
通过这个过程 你应该能够自己推导这个反向传播算法
but I think there are actually plenty of deep learning practitioners
但是实际上 我认为有很多深度学习从业者
that have seen the derivation at about the level you've
他们在反向传播算法推导的层次也和你
seen in this video and are already able to have
在视频中看到的差不多 而且能够
all the very intuitions and be able to implement this algorithm very effectively.
通过直觉非常高效地实现这个反向传播算法
If you are an expert in calculus,
如果你精通微积分
do see if you can derive the whole thing from scratch.
你可以试试看 自己能否从最开始推导整个过程
It is one of the very hardest pieces of math.
这个是数学中最难的部分
One of the very hardest derivations that I've seen in all of machine learning.
而且是我见过的最难推导的机器学习算法
Either way, if you implement this,
不管怎样 如果你能够推导这个
this will work and I think you have enough intuitions to tune and get it to work.
复杂的算法 那么你将会拥有很好的直觉来调试算法 使其能够正常工作
There's just one last detail I want to
另外 我想和你
share with you before you implement your neural network,
分享的最后一个细节是
which is how to initialize the weights of your neural network.
怎样正确的初始化神经网络的权重参数
It turns out that initializing your parameters,
也就是说 将你的参数
not to zero but randomly,
进行随机初始化 而不是初始化为0
turns out to be very important for training your neural network.
这对于训练你的神经网络非常重要
In the next video, you'll see why.
在下个视频中 我会告诉你原因